<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep learning | Juan Camilo Vasquez Correa</title>
    <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/profile.jpeg</url>
      <title>Deep learning</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonet</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/software/phonet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/software/phonet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/deep-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:12:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/deep-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speech is the most natural method of communication among humans. The speech signals contain many traits that reflect suitable information from the speaker, including the identity, emotions, or the presence of diseases which alter the quality of life of patients.
Automatic recognition of speech traits has many applications including the medical field; for instance, the detection, monitoring, and assessment of voice disorders allow the development of computer aided tools to support the diagnosis and evaluation/screening of patients; the recognition of emotions.
Traditional machine learning methods to recognize speech traits are limited by their capability to process raw speech signals, i.e., without any preprocessing or any feature extraction. During several years, the deployment of suitable systems required the knowledge of an expert in a specific topic to obtain the most informative features to model the information from data, which consumes time and resources that are not always available. This project aims to develop and test different architectures of DNNs to perform the automatic detection of different traits in speech. Two different approaches will be addressed: (1) the raw speech signal will be considered as the input, and (2) several features will be extracted from the signals and those feature vectors will be the input of the system. We will compare both approaches in order to conclude to which extent it is possible to work only with the raw signal and obtain interpretable results such that can be used in the clinical practice.
In this proposal, DNN-based methods will be considered to three different problems: (1) classification/detection of multiple voice disorders, (2) monitoring of patients, and (3) detection of emotions and other paralinguistic aspects from speech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal PD</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:29:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/multimodal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main aim of this project is to develop a method to evaluate the motor impairments and the neurological state of patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease using three bio-signals: speech, handwriting and gait. This research work is suitable for the development of computer aided tools to evaluate the motor impairments of patients with different neurodegenerative disorders considering information from different bio&amp;ndash;signals to take accurate decisions about the treatment of the patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multitask Learning Approach to Assess the Dysarthria Severity in Patients with Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multitask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multitask/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal assessment of Parkinson&#39;s disease: a deep learning approach</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multimodal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional Neural Network to Model Articulation Impairments in Patients with Parkinson&#39;s Disease.</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-convolutional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-convolutional/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
