<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COLCIENCIAS | Juan Camilo Vasquez Correa</title>
    <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/authors/colciencias/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jcvasquezc.github.io/authors/colciencias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>COLCIENCIAS</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/profile.jpeg</url>
      <title>COLCIENCIAS</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/authors/colciencias/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conexion Salud</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/conexion-salud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/conexion-salud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Study to measure the level of Communication and information technologies (TICs) in  the public Health Services institutions of Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;




  
  





  





  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/conexion.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic recognition of emotions from speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:46:20 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/emotions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human emotions detection considering speech signals is a field that has attracted the attention of the research community since the last years. Several situations where the human integrity and security is at risk have been addressed; particularly the analysis of speech in emergency calls or in call-centers, are an interesting scenario. This project aimed to develop a methodology to classify different types of emotions such as anger, anxiety, disgust, and desperation, in scenarios where the speech signal is contaminated with noise or is coded by telephone channels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PD speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/pdspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 09:10:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/pdspeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease (PD) is the second neurological condition more prevalent after Alheimer. It is fundamental identify early markers of the disease.  90% of people with PD present speech disorders, but only from 3% to 4% recieve speech treatment. In this project will be developed methodologies based on signal processing to establish if the speech signals represent an early marker of PD. Also will be applied machine learning techniques to develop methodologies that allow make an objective following about of speech quality in patients with PD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
