<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health-care | Juan Camilo Vasquez Correa</title>
    <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/health-care/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/health-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>health-care</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/profile.jpeg</url>
      <title>health-care</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/health-care/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Representation of Pathophysiology of Parkinsonian Dysarthria</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/rueda-2019-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/rueda-2019-feature/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apkinson</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/software/apkinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/software/apkinson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Apkinson1.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Apkinson2.png&#34; alt=&#34;drawing&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apkinson is an Android aplication to evaluate continuously the speech and movement symptoms of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s patients, providing a feedback mechanism about the current stage of the disease. The patients are asked to do different speech and movement exercises everyday, which are selected from an exercise bank that contains a total of 35 exercises. The speech exercises include the phonation of sustained vowels, diadochokinetic utterances, several sentences that the patient has to read, and the description of images that appear in the screen.  On the other hand, movement exercises are captured using the inertial sensors of the smartphone to evaluate symptoms in the upper and lower limbs, such as postural tremor, kinetic tremor, finger tapping, gait deficits, among others.&lt;br /&gt;
At the end of the exercise session, Apkinson evaluates the performance of the patient, while it keeps a register of the results from previous sessions. This analysis will allow the assessment of the progress of the disease of the patients.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  





  





  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/video_apkinson.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aprendizaje por transferencia en redes neuronales convolucionales para el diagnóstico y monitoreo de la enfermedad de Parkinson usando señales de voz en tres idiomas diferentes</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/teaching/cristian-rios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/teaching/cristian-rios/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conexion Salud</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/conexion-salud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/conexion-salud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Study to measure the level of Communication and information technologies (TICs) in  the public Health Services institutions of Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;





  
  





  





  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/conexion.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling of Speech Aspects in Parkinson’s Disease by Multitask Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/teaching/martin-strauss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/teaching/martin-strauss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurospeech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/software/neurospeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/software/neurospeech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VOT</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/vot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 09:20:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/vot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Automatic detection of voiced onset time (VOT) for assessment of pathological speech&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Third Frederick Jelinek Memorial Summer Workshop</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:35:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/remote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer’s disease (AD) is the most common neurodegenerative disorder. It generally deteriorates memory function, then language, then executive function to the point where simple activities of daily living (ADLs) become difficult. Parkinson’s disease (PD) is the second most common neurodegenerative disease, also primarily affecting individuals of advanced age. Its cardinal symptoms include akinesia, tremor, rigidity, and postural imbalance. Together, AD and PD afflict approximately 55 million people, and there is no cure. Currently, professional or informal caregivers look after these individuals, either at home or in long-term care facilities. Caregiving is already a great, expensive burden on the system, but things will soon become far worse. Populations of many nations are aging rapidly and, with over 12% of people above the age of 65 having either AD or PD, incidence rates are set to triple over the next few decades. Monitoring and assessment are vital, but current models are unsustainable. Patients need to be monitored regularly (e.g. to check if medication needs to be updated), which is expensive, time-consuming, and especially difficult when travelling to the closest neurologist is unrealistic. Monitoring patients using non-intrusive sensors to collect data during ADLs from speech, gait, and handwriting, can help to reduce the burden.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal PD</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:29:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/multimodal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main aim of this project is to develop a method to evaluate the motor impairments and the neurological state of patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease using three bio-signals: speech, handwriting and gait. This research work is suitable for the development of computer aided tools to evaluate the motor impairments of patients with different neurodegenerative disorders considering information from different bio&amp;ndash;signals to take accurate decisions about the treatment of the patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAPAS</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/tapas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:06:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/tapas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are an increasing number of people across Europe with debilitating speech pathologies (e.g., due to stroke, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s, etc). These groups face communication problems that can lead to social exclusion. They are now being further marginalised by a new wave of speech technology that is increasingly woven into everyday life but which is not robust to atypical speech. TAPAS is a Horizon 2020 Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions Innovative Training Network European Training Network (MSCA-ITN-ETN) project that aims to transform the well being of these people. The TAPAS work programme targets three key research problems: &lt;b&gt;(a)&lt;/b&gt; Detection: We will develop speech processing techniques for early detection of conditions that impact on speech production. The outcomes will be cheap and non-invasive diagnostic tools that provide early warning of the onset of progressive conditions such as Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s. &lt;b&gt;(b)&lt;/b&gt; Therapy: We will use newly-emerging speech processing techniques to produce automated speech therapy tools. These tools will make therapy more accessible and more individually targeted. Better therapy can increase the chances of recovering intelligible speech after traumatic events such a stroke or oral surgery. &lt;b&gt;&amp;copy;&lt;/b&gt; Assisted Living: We will re-design current speech technology so that it works well for people with speech impairments and also helps in making informed clinical choices. People with speech impairments often have other co-occurring conditions making them reliant on carers. Speech-driven tools for assisted-living are a way to allow such people to live more independently. TAPAS adopts an inter-disciplinary and multi-sectorial approach. The consortium includes clinical practitioners, academic researchers and industrial partners, with expertise spanning speech engineering, linguistics and clinical science. All members have expertise in some element of pathological speech. This rich network will train a new generation of 15 researchers, equipping them with the skills and resources necessary for lasting success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Analysis to Detect Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/perez-2019-natural/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/perez-2019-natural/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis and evaluation of handwriting in patients with Parkinson’s disease using kinematic, geometrical, and non-linear features</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/rios-2019-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/rios-2019-analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Cross-language Intelligibility Analysis of Parkinson’s Disease Patients Using Speech Recognition Technologies</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/hosseini-2019-automated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/hosseini-2019-automated/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech differences between CI users with pre-and postlingual onset of deafness detected by speech processing methods on voiceless to voice transitions</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vergara-2019-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vergara-2019-speech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multitask Learning Approach to Assess the Dysarthria Severity in Patients with Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multitask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multitask/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Non-linear Dynamics Approach to Classify Gait Signals of Patients with Parkinson’s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/perez-2018-non/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/perez-2018-non/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apkinson: A Mobile Solution for Multimodal Assessment of Patients with Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2019-apkinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2019-apkinson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Intelligibility Assessment of Parkinson&#39;s Disease with Diadochokinetic Exercises</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/parra-2018-automatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/parra-2018-automatic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal I-vectors to Detect and Evaluate Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/garcia-2018-multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/garcia-2018-multimodal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal assessment of Parkinson&#39;s disease: a deep learning approach</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-multimodal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeuroSpeech: An open-source software for Parkinson&#39;s speech analysis</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/orozco-2018-neurospeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/orozco-2018-neurospeech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonological i-Vectors to Detect Parkinson&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/garcia-2018-phonological/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/garcia-2018-phonological/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Representaciones tiempo-frecuencia basadas en sensores inerciales para caracterizar la marcha en la enfermedad de Parkinson</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/bedoya-2018-representaciones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/bedoya-2018-representaciones/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker models for monitoring Parkinson’s disease progression considering different communication channels and acoustic conditions</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2018-speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2018-speaker/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an automatic evaluation of the dysarthria level of patients with Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-towards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2018-towards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unobtrusive Monitoring of Speech Impairments of Parkinson&#39;s Disease Patients Through Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2018-unobtrusive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2018-unobtrusive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterisation of voice quality of Parkinson’s disease using differential phonological posterior features</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/cernak-2017-characterisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/cernak-2017-characterisation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional Neural Network to Model Articulation Impairments in Patients with Parkinson&#39;s Disease.</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-convolutional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-convolutional/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of acoustic conditions on algorithms to detect Parkinson&#39;s disease from speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-effect/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language independent assessment of motor impairments of patients with Parkinson’s disease using i-vectors</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/garcia-2017-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/garcia-2017-language/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-view representation learning via GCCA for multimodal analysis of Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-multi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-multi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the impact of non-modal phonation on phonological features</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/cernak-2017-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/cernak-2017-impact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parkinson&#39;s disease and aging: analysis of their effect in phonation and articulation of speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2017-parkinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2017-parkinson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonation and Articulation Analyses in Laryngeal Pathologies, Cleft Lip and Palate, and Parkinson’s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/jimenez-2017-phonation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/jimenez-2017-phonation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Model to Monitor the Neurological State and the Dysarthria Level of Patients with Parkinson’s Disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2017-speaker/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic detection of hypernasal speech of children with cleft lip and palate from spanish vowels and words using classical measures and nonlinear analysis</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/orozco-2016-automatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/orozco-2016-automatic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender-dependent gmm-ubm for tracking parkinson&#39;s disease progression from speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2016-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2016-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parkinson&#39;s Disease Progression Assessment from Speech Using GMM-UBM.</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2016-parkinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/arias-2016-parkinson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an automatic monitoring of the neurological state of Parkinson&#39;s patients from speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/orozco-2016-towards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/orozco-2016-towards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word accuracy and dynamic time warping to assess intelligibility deficits in patients with parkinsons disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2016-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2016-word/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic detection of Parkinson&#39;s disease from continuous speech recorded in non-controlled noise conditions</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2015-automatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2015-automatic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New computer aided device for real time analysis of speech of people with Parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2014-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2014-new/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PD speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/pdspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 09:10:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/pdspeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease (PD) is the second neurological condition more prevalent after Alheimer. It is fundamental identify early markers of the disease.  90% of people with PD present speech disorders, but only from 3% to 4% recieve speech treatment. In this project will be developed methodologies based on signal processing to establish if the speech signals represent an early marker of PD. Also will be applied machine learning techniques to develop methodologies that allow make an objective following about of speech quality in patients with PD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and implementation of an embedded system for real time analysis of speech from people with parkinson&#39;s disease</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2013-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/publication/vasquez-2013-design/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
