<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Signal processing | Juan Camilo Vasquez Correa</title>
    <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/signal-processing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/signal-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Signal processing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:29:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/img/profile.jpeg</url>
      <title>Signal processing</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/tags/signal-processing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal PD</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/multimodal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 06:29:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/multimodal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main aim of this project is to develop a method to evaluate the motor impairments and the neurological state of patients with Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease using three bio-signals: speech, handwriting and gait. This research work is suitable for the development of computer aided tools to evaluate the motor impairments of patients with different neurodegenerative disorders considering information from different bio&amp;ndash;signals to take accurate decisions about the treatment of the patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PD speech</title>
      <link>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/pdspeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 09:10:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jcvasquezc.github.io/project/pdspeech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease (PD) is the second neurological condition more prevalent after Alheimer. It is fundamental identify early markers of the disease.  90% of people with PD present speech disorders, but only from 3% to 4% recieve speech treatment. In this project will be developed methodologies based on signal processing to establish if the speech signals represent an early marker of PD. Also will be applied machine learning techniques to develop methodologies that allow make an objective following about of speech quality in patients with PD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
